<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>oxford math Institute</title><link>https://www.maths.ox.ac.uk/about-us/vacancies</link><description>oxford math Institute</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:17:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>College Vacancies in Mathematics</title><link>https://www.maths.ox.ac.uk/node/39835</link><description>Departmental staff are reminded that prior approval is usually needed from the Head of Department before accepting outside appointments such as these. If you have any queries about this requirement, please contact the HR team: @email .</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Postdoctoral Research Associate in Operator Algebras – Closing date: Wed, 19 Nov 2025 - 12:00</title><link>https://www.maths.ox.ac.uk/node/74482</link><description>We invite applications for a Postdoctoral Research Associate in Operator Algebras to work with Professor Stuart White at the Mathematical Institute, University of Oxford. The position is full time, fixed-term for two years, and supported by a grant from the Engineering and Physical Sciences Research Council (EPSRC), grant reference EP/X026647/1.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hooke Research Fellowship &amp; Glasstone Research Fellowship – Closing date: Fri, 21 Nov 2025 - 12:00</title><link>https://www.maths.ox.ac.uk/node/74452</link><description>We are seeking talented postdoctoral researchers to take up exciting Fellowship opportunities at the Mathematical Institute.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Titchmarsh Research Fellowship &amp; Glasstone Research Fellowship – Closing date: Fri, 21 Nov 2025 - 12:00</title><link>https://www.maths.ox.ac.uk/node/74453</link><description>We are seeking talented postdoctoral researchers to take up exciting Fellowship opportunities at the Mathematical Institute.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Postdoctoral Research Associate in Mathematical Physics (up to 2 posts) – Closing date: Fri, 28 Nov 2025 - 12:00</title><link>https://www.maths.ox.ac.uk/node/74528</link><description>We are currently inviting applications for up to two Postdoctoral Research Associates to work in the Mathematical Physics Group at the Mathematical Institute, University of Oxford. These are fixed-term positions for 36 months. These positions are funded by the UKRI Frontier Research grant (based on an ERC Advanced Grant, Schafer-Nameki). We anticipate the start-date of these positions to be no later than 1 October 2026.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hooke Research Fellow (Mathematics for the Environment) – Closing date: Fri, 28 Nov 2025 - 12:00</title><link>https://www.maths.ox.ac.uk/node/74531</link><description>We are seeking a talented postdoctoral researcher to take up an exciting Fellowship opportunity at the Mathematical Institute.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Postdoctoral Research Associate in Mathematics – Closing date: Mon, 01 Dec 2025 - 12:00</title><link>https://www.maths.ox.ac.uk/node/74283</link><description>We are currently inviting applications for a Postdoctoral Research Associate to work with Professors Jon Keating and Louis-Pierre Arguin at the Mathematical Institute, University of Oxford. This is a 3-year, fixed-term position, funded by a research grant from the UK Engineering and Physical Sciences Research Council. The starting date of this position is flexible with an earliest start date of 1 June 2026. We particularly welcome applications from individuals who are able to start between 1 June 2026 and 1 September 2026.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Postdoctoral Research Associate in Stochastic Analysis – Closing date: Fri, 05 Dec 2025 - 12:00</title><link>https://www.maths.ox.ac.uk/node/74773</link><description>We are currently inviting applications for a Postdoctoral Research Associate to work with Professor Massimiliano Gubinelli at the Mathematical Institute, University of Oxford. This is a 30 month, fixed-term position, funded by a Simons Foundation research grant. The successful candidate will be expected to take up this post as soon as possible, with a latest start date of1st October 2026.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Postdoctoral Research Associate in Stochastic Analysis – Closing date: Fri, 05 Dec 2025 - 12:00</title><link>https://www.maths.ox.ac.uk/node/74774</link><description>We are currently inviting applications for a Postdoctoral Research Associate to work with Professor Massimiliano Gubinelli at the Mathematical Institute, University of Oxford. This is a three-year, fixed-term position, funded by an UKRI Frontier research grant. The successful candidate will be expected to take up this post as soon as possible, with a latest start date of1st October 2026.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Regius Professorship of Mathematics – Closing date: Mon, 12 Jan 2026 - 12:00</title><link>https://www.maths.ox.ac.uk/node/74751</link><description>Mathematical Institute in associate with Merton College The Mathematical Institute and Merton College are seeking applications for the Regius Professorship of Mathematics, with effect from 1 October 2026 or as soon as possible thereafter. The professorship will become available on the retirement of the inaugural postholder, Professor Sir Andrew Wiles FRS.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>